





### Summary

Jump to Section

Offering nearly 9 years of experience in Webmethods-AWS Solution Architecture, AWS components & APIs Operating Systems (Windows and Linux)

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Comprehensive exposure to Web Services, Restful Services, SOA Architecture; experienced on AWS Codedelpoy, AWS Code Build, AWS Code Commit, AWS Code Pipeline

Strong technical background in designing & implementing Cloud solutions with AWS Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Elastic Load Balancer (ELB), S3, Auto Scaling, RDS, Cloud Watch & AWS Services

Developed solutions to optimize, enhance, manage the clients' business in the best possible way with end-to-end execution of the solution identification

Exhibited excellence in Cloud Mgration, Consolidation & Transformation Projects, Cloud Services, Solutions, Consultancy & Deployment and Data Center Transformation Services

Assisted customers in creating Virtual Private Cloud, Public, Private subnets as per requirement into various availability zones

# **Work Experience**

Sears Holdings as Sr Technical Associate AWS-Webmethods Aug 2016 to Aug 2020

Role:

AWS

Mgrated data from on premises application web-methods Integration server Environment to AWS cloud Planned & created a lift & shift process model, EC2 Linux/Amazon linux AMI to host the application & Security groups Designed EBS and EFS volumes; created AM using sanpshots of the EBS volumes & Instance stores Mapped users/groups roles to appropriate AWS service; prepared, modified & maintained policies and tagged

users/groups to appropriate policies; configured AWS CLI with AWS EC2 machine

Worked on Simple Storage Service, created S3 buckets, designed S3 Lifecycle Policies as per the need of the architecture; monitored & worked on S3 Performance ,Transfer Acceleration ,Cross region Replication

Used boot script for automation in EC2 instances by gathering Userdata and Metadata of EC2 instances & developed database instance from manual and automated backup snapshots; created PITR database from Automated Snapshots

Set- up the RDS instances in PRD ENV; configured RDS with VPC Creation for public and private networks; configured Read replicas and Multi-AZ nodes for RDS database

Created, configured VPC with Route tables, Subnets & developed private subnets for DB servers Developed:

- NAT instances and NAT gateways to allow more security and smooth flow of traffic
- NACLS and configured with appropriate subnets to allow smooth and secure flow of traffic; configured port in NACL's & VPC flow logs to track IP adresses

Configured DNS service with AWS to route traffic; used policies to divert traafic using SImple, Weighted, Failover, Gelocation

Webmethods

# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Infrastructure) to communicate between applications via Webmethods/ESB

Deployed packages from DEV to QA and from QA to PRD post approval, Whitelist IP's on IS ,DMZ's and Mediator server

Created native service in Business UI (Centrasite), Virtualize Native service, deployed Virtual service in Mediators, updated the Endpoints in Centrasite and deploy it in Mediators

Developed & configured DMZ ports namely Gateway External and Gateway Registration to communicate with external clients; configured SSL certificates on DMZ servers to provide more security

Requested CACERTS from ICA, created key aliases to Keystore, created jks keystore using keytool, imported CACERTS, installed client certificate in Trustore

Enabled and disabled ports, adapters MQ Listeners and MQ Connections; increased the logging level on IS servers Worked on SSL handshake issues on service and server; analysed wrapper logs ,updated system & services with PCI data to be TLS1.2 Complaint as it includes financial information

Liaised with SAG & other application teams in troubleshooting & Correction of Error(COE) during P-1; captured diagnostic logs using diagnostic utility, installed SAG Fixes using update manager; opened INC to SAG to further investigate issue

Configured Crontab which includes Schedule Server restart, Purging of the logs, gatering monitoring data for further use

Experienced in Kibana Tool Used to monitor ESB transactions and troubleshot issue during the functioning of tool; designed dashboards using Kibana Tools to monitor traffic effectively

# HCL Technology as AWS Associate

Apr 2013 to Aug 2016

Client: Johnson & Johnson

Technology. AWS, IAM, No SQL Database, Simple Storage Service, EC2, EBS, EFS, Buckets, RDS, Amazon 53 Route, Read Replicas, Multi AZ failover. VPC, AMI, Logstash, Kibana, SQL, DynamoDB, Backup & Recovery, WebMethods IS82, IS97 Platform, Broker, Trading Partner, MWS, HP-UX, LINUX Operating System.

Environment: Web-Methods Integration server 8.x, Trading Network 8.x, Web-Methods developer 8.x, Web-methods 9.x .Unix

Highlights:

Devised & implemented strategies to build mindshare and broad use of AWS within a wide range of customers and partners

Possess knowledge on STS, Hypervisors , Parameter Store, AWS Config, Guard duty

Provided protection against DDOS attack using AWS WAF and AWS shield; managed KMS keys within services through AWS (AWS Inspector and Trusted Advisor) for security and compliance

#### IBM GPS as Web-Methods Administrator Jan 2012 to Apr 2013

Worked on IBM payroll with GAP INC & contributed as Webmethods Administrator/PRD Support in IBM GPS for GAP Technology.

WebMethods IS82, IS97 Platform,Broker,Trading Partner,MWS, HP-UX, LINUX Operating System Web-Wethods Integration server 8.x,Trading Network 8.x, Web-Wethods developer 8.x, Web-methods 9.x, Uni

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Maharishi Dayanand University in 2011

^ Back to Top

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
AWS, IAM, No SQL Database		
Simple Storage Service, EC2, EBS, EFS		
Buckets, RDS, Amazon 53 Route		
Read Replicas, Multi AZ failover		
VPC, AM, Logstash, Kibana		
SQL, DynamoDB, Backup & Recovery		
Auto Scalling Groups, Rouyte S3		
KMS, ALB, Trusted Advisor		
Aws Inspector, WebMethods IS82, IS97		
LINUX Operatiing System		

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.